<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<FrameLayout android:orientation="vertical" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="fill_parent"
  xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android" xmlns:ads="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto">
   
    <RelativeLayout android:background="#e6ffffff" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="fill_parent">
        <LinearLayout android:orientation="vertical" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content"  android:layout_alignParentLeft="true" android:layout_alignParentTop="true" android:layout_alignParentRight="true">
            <TextView android:textSize="25.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ffffffff" android:gravity="center_horizontal" android:background="#fffc8002" android:padding="10.0dip" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="Bhagat Singh" android:singleLine="true" />
            <ImageView android:layout_gravity="center_horizontal" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:src="@drawable/bhagat" />
            <ScrollView android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip">
                <LinearLayout android:orientation="vertical" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content">
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Name : " />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="Bhagat Singh" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Born : " />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="September 28, 1907, Jaranwala Tehsil" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Died :" />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="March 23, 1931, Lahore, Pakistan" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Parents :" />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="Sardar Kishan Singh Sandhu, Vidyavati" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Education :" />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="National College, Lahore, Dayanand Anglo-Vedic Schools System" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="vertical" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="15.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="20.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff0001f5" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Biography of Bhagat Singh" />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:text="Bhagat Singh was born on 27 September 1907 in Lyallpur, Punjab, British India &amp; died on 23 March 1931 Lahore, Punjab, British India, was an Indian freedom fighter, considered to be one of the most influential revolutionaries of the Indian independence movement.Bhagat Singh was born into a sikh family to Sardar Kishan Singh and Vidyavati in the Khatkar Kalan village near Banga in the Lyallpur district of Punjab. Singh’s given name of Bhagat means “devotee”, and he was nicknamed “Bhaganwala” by his grandmother, meaning “The lucky one”. He came from a patriotic Jatt Sikh family, some of whom had participated in movements supporting the independence of India and others who had served in Maharaja Ranjit Singh’s army. His grandfather, Arjun Singh, was a follower of Swami Dayananda Saraswati’s Hindu reformist movement, Arya Samaj, which would carry a heavy influence on Singh. His uncles, Ajit Singh and Swaran Singh, as well as his father were members of the Ghadar Party, led by Kartar Singh Sarabha Grewal and Har Dayal. Ajit Singh was forced to flee to Persia because of pending cases against him while Swaran Singh was hanged on 19 December 1927 for his involvement in the Kakori train robbery of 1925. \n \n He is often referred to as Shaheed Bhagat Singh. Singh, as a teenager, had studied European revolutionary movements and was attracted to anarchism and communism. He became involved in numerous revolutionary organizations. He quickly rose through the ranks of the Hindustan Republican Association (HRA) and became one of its leaders, converting it to the Hindustan Socialist Republican Association (HSRA). Singh gained support when he underwent a 64-day fast in jail, demanding equal rights for Indian and British political prisoners. He was hanged for shooting a police officer in response to the killing of veteran freedom fighter Lala Lajpat Rai. His legacy prompted youth in India to begin fighting for Indian independence and also increased the rise of socialism in India. \n \n In 1923, Bhagat famously won an essay competition set by the Punjab Hindi Sahitya Sammelan. This grabbed the attention of members of the Punjab Hindi Sahitya Sammelan including its General Secretary Professor Bhim Sen Vidyalankar. At this age, he quoted famous Punjabi literature and discussed the Problems of the Punjab. He read a lot of poetry and literature which was written by Punjabi writers and his favourite poet was Allama Iqbal from Sialkot. \n \n In his teenage years, Bhagat Singh started studying at the National College in Lahore, but ran away from home to escape early marriage, and became a member of the organisation Naujawan Bharat Sabha (“Youth Society of India”). In the Naujawan Bharat Sabha, Singh and his fellow revolutionaries grew popular amongst the youth. He also joined the Hindustan Republican Association through introduction by history teacher, Professor Vidyalankar, which had prominent leaders like Ram Prasad Bismil, Chandrashekhar Azad and Ashfaqulla Khan. It is believed that he went to Kanpur to attempt free Kakori train robbery prisoners from the jail, but returned to Lahore for unknown reasons. On the day of Dasara in October 1926, a bomb was blasted in Lahore, and Bhagat Singh was arrested for his alleged involvement in this Dasara Bomb Case in 29 May 1927, and was released on a bail of Rs.60,000 after about five weeks of his arrest. He wrote for and edited Urdu and Punjabi newspapers published from Amritsar. In September 1928, a meeting of various revolutionaries from across India was called at Delhi under the banner of the Kirti Kissan Party. Bhagat Singh was the secretary of the meet. His later revolutionary activities were carried out as a leader of this association. \n \n While in prison, Bhagat Singh and two others had written a letter to the Viceroy asking him to treat them as prisoners of war and hence to execute them by firing squad and not by hanging. Prannath Mehta, Bhagat Singh’s friend, visited him in the jail on 20 March, four days before his execution, with a draft letter for clemency, but he declined to sign it. \n \n                         " />
                    </LinearLayout>
                </LinearLayout>
            </ScrollView>
        </LinearLayout>
        
    </RelativeLayout>
</FrameLayout>
