<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<FrameLayout android:orientation="vertical" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="fill_parent"
  xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android" xmlns:ads="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res-auto">
    
    <RelativeLayout android:background="#e6ffffff" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="fill_parent">
        <LinearLayout android:orientation="vertical" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_above="@id/adView" android:layout_alignParentLeft="true" android:layout_alignParentTop="true" android:layout_alignParentRight="true">
            <TextView android:textSize="25.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ffffffff" android:gravity="center_horizontal" android:background="#fffc8002" android:padding="10.0dip" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="Lal Bahadur Shashtri" android:singleLine="true" />
            <ImageView android:layout_gravity="center_horizontal" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:src="@drawable/lal_bahadur_sastri" />
            <ScrollView android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip">
                <LinearLayout android:orientation="vertical" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content">
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Name : " />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="Lal Bahadur Shashtri" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Born : " />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="October 2, 1904, Ramnagar" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Died :" />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="January 11, 1966, Tashkent, Uzbekistan" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Parents :" />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="Ramdulari Devi, Sharada Prasad Srivastava" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Children :" />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="Anil Shastri, Sunil Shastri, Ashok Shastri, Hari Shastri,Suman Shastri, Kusum Shastri" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Education :" />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="Mahatma Gandhi Kashi Vidyapeeth (1926)" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="horizontal" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff00a200" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Awards :" />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:text="Bharat Ratna" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                    <LinearLayout android:orientation="vertical" android:layout_width="fill_parent" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginLeft="10.0dip" android:layout_marginTop="15.0dip" android:layout_marginRight="10.0dip">
                        <TextView android:textSize="20.0dip" android:textStyle="bold" android:textColor="#ff0001f5" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginRight="5.0dip" android:text="Biography of Lal Bahadur Shashtri" />
                        <TextView android:textSize="15.0dip" android:textColor="#fffc8002" android:layout_width="wrap_content" android:layout_height="wrap_content" android:layout_marginTop="10.0dip" android:text="Lal Bahadur Shastri was born on 2 October 1904 in Mughalsarai, Banaras, United Province, British India now Mughalsarai, Chandali, Uttar Pradesh, India &amp; died on 11 January 1966 in Tashkent, Uzbek SSR, Soviet Union,was the second Prime Minister of the Republic of India and a leader of the Indian National Congress party. \n \n Shastri joined the Indian independence movement in the 1920s. Deeply impressed and influenced by Congress leader Mahatma Gandhi, he became a loyal follower, first of Gandhi, and then of Jawaharlal Nehru. Following independence in 1947, he joined the latter’s government and became one of Prime Minister Nehru’s principal lieutenants, first as Railways Minister (1951–56), and then in a variety of other functions, including Home Minister. Shastri was chosen as Nehru’s successor owing to his adherence of Nehruvian socialism after Nehru’s daughter Indira Gandhi turned down Congress President K. Kamaraj’s offer of premiership. \n \n Shastri as Prime Minister continued Nehru’s policies of non-alignment and socialism. He became a national hero following the Indo-Pakistan War of 1965. The war was formally ended in the Tashkent Agreement of 10 January 1966; he died the following day, still in Tashkent, of a heart attack. \n \n His father, Shri Sharada Srivastava Prasad, was a school teacher, who later became a clerk in the Revenue Office at Allahabad. Shastri’s father died when he was only an year old. His mother, Ramdulari Devi, took him and his two sisters to her father’s house and settled down there. \n \n Shastri ji was educated at East Central Railway Enter college in Mughalsarai and Varanasi. He graduated with a first-class degree from the Kashi Vidyapeeth in 1926. He was given the title Shastri (“Scholar”). The title was a bachelor’s degree awarded by the Vidya Peeth, but it stuck as part of his name. Shastri was influenced by major Indian nationalist leaders including Tilak. Later he was greatly influenced by the socialism ofJawaharlal Nehru, whose left-wing faction in the Congress party he would eventually join. \n \n In 16 May 1928, Shastri married Lalita Devi of Mirzapur. He had fivechildren, including Hari Krishna Shashtri, Anil Shastri and Sunil Shashtri, who were all Congress politicians. His son Anil Shastri is still a senior leader of the Congress party. \n \n Shastri, who belonged to the Kayastha caste, dropped his surname Srivastava as it indicated his caste and he was against the caste system, a major principle of the Gandhian movement. Shastri also enrolled himself as a life member of the Servants of the People Society and began to work for the upliftment of the Harijans under Gandhi’s direction at Muzaffarpur. Later he became the President of the Society. \n \n Shastri joined the Indian independence movement in 1921. His early activities included participation in the non-cooperation movement for which he was jailed briefly by the British. He was let off as he was then still a minor. \n \n Shastri participated in the Salt Satyagraha in 1930. He was imprisoned fortwo and a half years. Later, he worked as the Organizing Secretary of the Parliamentary Board of U.P. in 1937. In 1940, he was sent to prison for one year, for offering individual Satyagraha support to the freedom movement. \n \n On 8 August 1942, Mahatma Gandhi issued the Quit India speech at Gowalia Tank in Mumbai, demanding that the British leave India. Shastri, who had just then come out after a year in prison, travelled to Allahabad. For a week, he sent instructions to the freedom fighters from Jawaharlal Nehru home, Anand Bhavan. A few days later, he was arrested and imprisoned until 1946. Shastri spent almost nine years in jail in total. During his stays in prison, he spent time reading books and became familiar with the works of western philosophers, revolutionaries and social reformers. He also translated the autobiography of Marie Curie into Hindi. \n \n Following India’s independence, Shastri was appointed Parliamentary Secretary in his home state, Uttar Pradesh. He became the Minister of Police and Transport under Govind Ballabh Pant’s Chief Ministership on 15 Aug 1947 following Rafi Ahmed Kidwai’s departure to become minister at centre. As the Transport Minister, he was the first to appoint women conductors. As the minister in charge of the Police Department, he ordered that police use jets of water instead of lathis to disperse unruly crowds. His tenure as police minister ( As Home Minister was called prior to 1950) saw successful curbing of communal riots in 1947, mass migration and resettlement of refugees and break-in and putting of idols in disputed Babri Masjid – Ram Janmabhoomi complex on 22 Dec 1949. \n \n In 1951, Shastri was made the General Secretary of the All-India Congress Committee, with Jawaharlal Nehru as the Prime Minister. He was directly responsible for the selection of candidates and the direction of publicity and electioneering activities. He played an important role in the landslide successes of the Congress Party in the Indian General Elections of 1952, 1957 and 1962. In 1952, he successfully contested UP Vidhansabha from Soraon North cum Phulpur West seat and won getting over 69% of vote. He was believed to be retained as home minister of UP, but in a surprise move was called to Centre as minister by Nehru. He was elected to Rajyasabha from Uttar Pradesh w.e.f. 03 April 1952. He served as the Minister of Railways and Transport in the Central Cabinet from 13 May 1952 to 7 December 1956. In Sep 1956, he offered his resignation after a railway accident at Mahbubnagar that led to 112 deaths. However, Nehru did not accept his resignation. Three months later, he resigned accepting moral and constitutional responsibility for a railway accident at Ariyalur in Tamil Nadu that resulted in 144 deaths. While speaking in Parliament on the incident, Nehru stated that he was accepting the resignation because it would set an example in constitutional propriety and not because Shastri was in any way responsible for the accident. \n \n In 1957, Shastri returned to the Cabinet following the General Elections, first as the Minister for Transport and Communications, and then as the Minister of Commerce and Industry. In 1961, he became Minister for Home. As Union Home Minister he was instrumental in appointing the Committee on Prevention of Corruption under the Chairmanship of K. Santhanam. \n \n Jawaharlal Nehru died in office on 27 May 1964 and left a void. ThenCongress Party President K. Kamaraj was instrumental in making Shastri Prime Minister on 9 June. Shastri, though mild-mannered and soft-spoken, was a Nehruvian socialist and thus held appeal to those wishing to prevent the ascent of conservative right-winger Morarji Desai. \n \n Shastri retained many members of Nehru’s Council of Ministers. T. T. Krishnamachari was retained as the Finance Minister of India, as was Defence Minister Yashwantrao Chavan. He appointed Swaran Singh to succeed him as External Affairs Minister. He also appointed Indira Gandhi, daughter of Jawaharlal Nehru and former Congress President, as the Minister of Information and Broadcasting. Gulzarilal Nanda continued as the Minister of Home Affairs. \n \n Shastri’s tenure witnessed the Madras anti-Hindi agitation of 1965. The government of India had for a long time made an effort to establish Hindi as the sole national language of India. This was resisted by the non-Hindi speaking states particularly Madras State. To calm the situation, Shastri took the advice of Indira Gandhi and gave assurances that English wouldcontinue to be used as the official language as long the non-Hindi speaking states wanted. The riots subsided after Shastri’s assurance, as did the student agitation. \n \n Shastri continued Nehru’s socialist economic policies with central planning. He promoted the White Revolution – a national campaign to increase the production and supply of milk – by supporting the Amul milk co-operative of Anand, Gujarat and creating the National Dairy Development Board. While speaking on the chronic food shortages across the country, Shastri urged people to voluntarily give up one meal so that the saved food could be distributed to the affected populace. During the 22-day war with Pakistan in 1965, Shastri created the slogan of “Jai Jawan Jai Kisan” (“Hail the soldier, Hail the farmer”), underlining the need to boost India’s food production. Shastri also promoted the Green Revolution. Though he was a socialist, Shastri stated that India cannot have a regimented type of economy. \n \n Prime Minister Shastri died in Tashkent due to a heart attack the day after signing the Tashkent Declaration. He was eulogised as a national hero and the Vijay Ghat memorial established in his memory. Upon his death, Gulzarilal Nanda once again assumed the role of Acting Prime Minister until the Congress Parliamentary Party elected Indira Gandhi over Morarji Desai to officially succeed Shastri. \n \n Shastri’s sudden death has led to persistent conspiracy theories that he was poisoned. The first inquiry into his death was conducted by the Raj Narain Inquiry, as it came to be known, however did not come up with any conclusions and today no record of this inquiry exists with the Indian Parliament’s library.It was alleged that no post-mortem was done on Shastri, but the Indian government in 2009, claimed it did have a report of a medical investigation conducted by Shastri’s personal physician Dr. R.N. Chugh and some Russian doctors. Furthermore, the Prime Minister’s Office (PMO) revealed that there was no record of any destruction or loss of documents in the PMO having a bearing on Shastri’s death. \n \n The possible existence of a conspiracy was covered in India by the Outlook magazine. In 2009, when Anuj Dhar, the author of the book, CIA’s Eye on South Asia, asked the Prime Minister’s Office under an RTI plea (Right to Information Act), to declassify a document supposedly related to Shastri’s death, the PMO refused to oblige, reportedly citing that this could lead to harming of foreign relations, cause disruption in the country and cause breach of parliamentary privileges. \n \n An epic poetry book in Hindi titled Lalita Ke Aansoo written by Krant M. L. Verma was published in 1978. In this book the tragic story about the death of Shastri has been narrated through the mouth of his wife Lalita Shastri. \n \n Ramachandra Guha argued that Shastri shared little in common with his predecessor Jawaharlal Nehru. While Shastri preferred peace with Pakistan, writing to a friend after the Indo-Pakistani War in 1965 that the problems between both countries should be settled amicably, he had previously displayed a knack for taking quick and decisive actions during the war. He swiftly took the advice of his commanders, and ordered a strike across the Punjab border. This was in stark contrast to Nehru who in a similar situation in 1962, had refused to call in the air force to relieve the pressure on the ground troops. At the end of the conflict, Shastri flamboyantly posed for a photograph on top of a captured Patton tank. \n \n However, in common with Nehru, Shastri was a secularist who refused to mix religion with politics. In a public meeting held at the Ram Lila grounds in Delhi, a few days after the ceasefire, he complained against a BBC report which claimed that Shastri’s identity as a Hindu meant that he was ready for a war with Pakistan. \n \n Although Shastri had been a cabinet minister for many years in the 1950s, he was poor when he died. All he owned at the end was an old car, which he had bought in instalments from the government and for which he still owed money. He was a member of Servants of India society (which included Gandhiji, Lala Lajpat Rai, Gopal Krishna Gokhle) which asked all its members to shun accumulation of private property and remain in public life as servants of people. He was the first railway minister who resigned from office following a major train accident as he felt moral responsibility. \n \n Shastri was known for his honesty and humility throughout his life. He was the first person to be posthumously awarded the Bharat Ratna, and a memorial “Vijay Ghat” was built for him in Delhi. Several educational institutes, Lal Bahadur Shastri National Academy of Administration (Mussorie, Uttarakhand) is after his name these were some examples. The Shastri Indo-Canadian Institute was named after Shastri due to his role in promoting scholarly activity between India and Canada. Today Lal Bhadur Shastri Memorial run by Lal Bahadur Shastri National Memorial Trust, is situated next to 10 Janpath his residence as Prime Minister, at 1, Motilal Nehru Place, New Delhi. In 2011, on Shastri’s 45th death anniversary, Uttar Pradesh Government announced to renovate Shastri’s ancestral house at Ramnagar in Varanasi and declared plans to convert it into a biographical museum. \n \n The International Airport at the City of Varanasi is named after him. \n \n A Monument and a street is named after him in the city of Tashkent, Uzbekistan. \n \n A stadium is named after him in the city of Hyderabad, Andhrapradesh \n \n In 2005, the Government of India created a chair in his honour in the field of democracy and governance at Delhi University. \n \n" />
                    </LinearLayout>
                </LinearLayout>
            </ScrollView>
        </LinearLayout>
        
    </RelativeLayout>
</FrameLayout>
